<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A voice from the close or inner prison unto all the upright in heart, whether they are bond or free.</title>
            <author>J. P. (John Perrot), d. 1671?.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1662</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 57 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 12 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A54453</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1640</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R217888</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99829531</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99829531</idno>
            <idno type="VID">33971</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A54453)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 33971)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1996:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A voice from the close or inner prison unto all the upright in heart, whether they are bond or free.</title>
                  <author>J. P. (John Perrot), d. 1671?.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>24 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for the author,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1662.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>By John Perrot.</note>
                  <note>The first leaf is blank; title page is A2.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Woodbrooke College Library, Birmingham.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Christian life --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:33971:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A VOICE FROM THE Cloſe or Inner PRISON, UNTO ALL THE Upright in Heart, Whether they are BOND OR FREE.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for the Author, 1662.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:33971:2"/>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:33971:2"/>
            <head>A Voice from the cloſe or inner Priſon unto the upright in heart, whether they are Bond or free.</head>
            <p>THe night of thick darkneſs, or ignorance, bondage and affliction <hi>is far ſpent; the day of Redemption,</hi> the wel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come year of general <hi>Jubilee,</hi> and <hi>glorious liberty of the Sons of God</hi> is at hand; the <hi>Day-Star</hi> of the lightſom <hi>Morning</hi> is already riſen in the hearts of hundreds and thouſands of <hi>Saints:</hi> Yea clouds of <hi>Angels,</hi> or miniſtring Spirits are im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powered, and coming from the heavenly <hi>Temple,</hi> to proclaim and publiſh it by ſound of <hi>Trumpet.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>By terrible things in righteouſneſs will the God of Salvation</hi> now anſwer them that have waited on him: His ſwift meſſengers from above are commiſſionated to pour their <hi>Vials</hi> forth, and deſtroy the <hi>third part</hi> of all that grows in the <hi>earthly</hi> nature, or bodily form of things, as alſo of all creatures whoſe life is in a troubled boyling <hi>Sea;</hi> and many men muſt <hi>die</hi> by the <hi>bitter wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters</hi> of affliction, who have not faith to ſweeten them by the <hi>tree of Life,</hi> being caſt into them: yea the very <hi>heavenly Lights</hi> them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, whether that <hi>rule by day</hi> or <hi>by night, viz.</hi> Sun, Moon and Stars, muſt loſe the <hi>third part</hi> of their luſtre; and <hi>woe, woe, woe, to the Inhabitants of the earth,</hi> by reaſon of the other voices and trumpets that are for to follow.</p>
            <p>But oh ye <hi>meek</hi> ones <hi>of the earth,</hi> that have <hi>ſought righteouſneſs and meekneſs,</hi> who therefore have been, are, and ſhall be hidden in the <hi>day of the Lord's anger;</hi> the time is coming, and now is, when the <hi>Holy one of Iſrael</hi> ſhall beautifie you with <hi>Salvation</hi> to the aſtoniſhment of <hi>earthly kindreds and people.</hi> You that have <hi>ſowne</hi> long in <hi>tears,</hi> the time of reaping the <hi>joyful harveſt</hi> of all your labours, travels, hardſhips and ſufferings, inward and out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, is at hand, and <hi>your joy</hi> is of that <hi>new nature, that no man can take from you.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Oh ye that have long obſcured your ſelves in ſilence to ſeek the <hi>pearl of price,</hi> even the innocent, harmleſſe, patient, long-ſuffering
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:33971:3"/>
ſuffering life (by the blood) of the <hi>Lamb,</hi> which as it loſt its living luſtre in earthly eaſe, power, and proſperity; ſo of late hath it ſhined forth to all beholders in burning fiery <hi>trials,</hi> and having diſcovered this <hi>inheritance of the Saints in light,</hi> have for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaken and ſold all to purchaſe it. Behold the clear <hi>evidence</hi> of your matchleſs <hi>wiſdom,</hi> and immortal ſtate will ſoon appear, for all that's mortal will ſhrink and conſume, in that <hi>fervent heat,</hi> whereby the old worlds <hi>Elements</hi> or Foundations <hi>ſhall melt,</hi> and <hi>the heavens</hi> of viſible worſhips themſelves will <hi>paſs away with a great noiſe;</hi> then will that which <hi>cannot be ſhaken</hi> or conſumed re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main; not impaired but improved in virtue, ſtrength and power, convincing both apoſtate Profeſſor and open Prophane, between whom ye have ſuffered as fools gladly, that you have wiſely <hi>choſen the better part,</hi> by keeping <hi>the word of Chriſt's patience</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out <hi>fainting.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To you <hi>ſhall come the firſt Dominion,</hi> that ſtand as <hi>Towers</hi> or <hi>He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goats</hi> of the <hi>flock,</hi> having withſtood all encounters both within and without againſt Satan and his inſtruments; enabled there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto not by a <hi>ſound of words,</hi> but by an <hi>Almighty power,</hi> whereby <hi>through weakneſs</hi> being <hi>made ſtrong,</hi> and willing by reſiſting even <hi>unto blood,</hi> to overcome; you have not minded the conqueſt that <hi>ſaves</hi> Life in ſtead of <hi>looſing</hi> it, but with a ready willing mind yeelding to the loſs of all in <hi>that war,</hi> wherein is <hi>no diſcharge.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>You that can ſtand ſtill in this manner reſign'd and ſincerely given up into the will and <hi>cuſtody of your faithful Creator,</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out a double mind that conſults to hear what fleſh and blood can ſay, which <hi>cannot inherit</hi> that glorious <hi>kingdom</hi> of God, conſiſting in <hi>righteouſneſs, peace, and joy in the holy Ghoſt;</hi> nothing can hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der your admittance thereunto, whoſe union in <hi>death,</hi> and ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferings is ſo firm with <hi>Chriſt,</hi> who is the <hi>reſurrection and the life;</hi> that over worldly <hi>diſtreſſe</hi> and <hi>tribulations</hi> of all kinds, you are be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come <hi>more than Conquerors</hi> through him that <hi>loves you.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Captain of our Salvation</hi> hath led the way before us, and all you that have thus followed, <hi>the gates of hell</hi> it ſelf can never prevail to hinder your intereſt in his reign and glory: Neverthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs <hi>Satan's winnowings and ſiftings</hi> of you may be for ſome ſmall time frequent and many, until by your <hi>finiſhing</hi> upon the <hi>Croſs</hi> your <hi>Fathers work,</hi> your hearts and ſoules become <hi>dry places,</hi>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:33971:3"/>
wherein though the unclean ſpirit of this world <hi>ſeeks</hi> its <hi>reſt, yet finds none;</hi> and the <hi>Prince</hi> thereof, being thus <hi>judged hath nothing,</hi> when he cometh <hi>in you:</hi> for as there is no way to kill the fear of <hi>Death,</hi> but by loving it in order to an <hi>abiding life,</hi> ſo, no <hi>reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection</hi> can be to <hi>life,</hi> but by <hi>dying</hi> to all on this ſide it; and in this <hi>Grave</hi> myſtical or litteral, wherein <hi>no man</hi> of the meer firſt or natural birth, which is of the earth earthly, <hi>ever lay,</hi> are al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes buried thoſe carnal fears, vain hopes and falſe joys, which are Satans various Engines of <hi>deceiveable unrighteouſneſs,</hi> to cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt and beguile <hi>unſtable</hi> ſoules, whoſe converſation ſtill is on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in the <hi>changable glory</hi> of the <hi>firſt</hi> or <hi>ſecond heavens,</hi> but are not yet taken up into the <hi>third,</hi> where the <hi>hidden Manna</hi> remaines <hi>incorruptible</hi> within the <hi>Vail</hi> of all tranſcient miniſtrations, though pure and beautiful in their kind and ſeaſon; there on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſtands the true <hi>tree</hi> of everlaſting <hi>life</hi> for all that come to feed upon, even in <hi>the midſt of the Paradiſe of God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This is that pleaſant lovely food that cauſes to <hi>hunger no more</hi> after carnal <hi>husky</hi> comforts of the <hi>old world,</hi> without which, man may live but not by <hi>bread alone,</hi> though ſpiritual meat, and <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gels food,</hi> but by <hi>every word</hi> coming forth from the <hi>mouth</hi> of the <hi>living God,</hi> not as 'tis onely written on paper, but on the <hi>fleſhly tables of his heart,</hi> where God <hi>hath ſet the world,</hi> which being reſtored, or <hi>renewed</hi> by a <hi>right ſpirit within him,</hi> does become an inward <hi>Paradiſe,</hi> and in that is <hi>Chriſt</hi> the <hi>living Word,</hi> who makes to live for ever, yea out-live all ſtorms as well as ſun-ſhines of this lower outward world, with a <hi>growing</hi> youth and beauty.</p>
            <p>But to ſuch as have not yet gained this <hi>Crown incorruptible,</hi> and nevertheleſs are ſtill lawfully ſtriving for the <hi>maſtery,</hi> by a holy <hi>temperance in all things;</hi> this time of general <hi>reſtitution,</hi> which is at hand, will much facilitate their courſe, becauſe the brethrens <hi>accuſer</hi> ſhall be <hi>bound</hi> in chaines to his place, not only from <hi>bruiſing</hi> the outward man with trouble and torment, but al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo from <hi>ſeducing</hi> the inward man with his falſe glaſs or gloſs, which he is wont to preſent before, as well refined, as groſſe ſelf-lovers, thereby <hi>inticing</hi> ſouls who are not fixt upon their <hi>in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible rock of Ages,</hi> to thoſe enſnaring treats and entertain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments that are abundant in his <hi>airy principality.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:33971:4"/>Behold alſo the time is come that the <hi>Bondwoman and her ſeed</hi> are to be caſt out, the true Heirs or <hi>Children of the Free</hi> muſt now <hi>in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herit,</hi> who have hitherto <hi>ſtood ſtill</hi> in an obedient Child-like <hi>free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi> to be <hi>offered</hi> up as <hi>Sacrifices,</hi> yea, <hi>ſlain all the day long for the Lamb's ſake,</hi> and <hi>led as ſheep to the ſlaughter:</hi> For although the Sons of <hi>Concubines</hi> have been <hi>ſent away</hi> into the world <hi>with gifts,</hi> whereby they have, as <hi>rich</hi> and <hi>full,</hi> publiſh't their own glory, ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther than in the <hi>Croſs of Chriſt Jeſus;</hi> yet the <hi>more enduring Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance that fades not away,</hi> or the Inheritance, which can never be loſt or alienated, belongs to thoſe <hi>Free-born Children</hi> of a greater than <hi>Abraham,</hi> who like <hi>Princes</hi> have <hi>wreſtled</hi> and <hi>prevailed,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe annointed with that ſpirit which ſuffers no <hi>foyle,</hi> but by being in <hi>deaths often,</hi> and willingly receiving the ſentence there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of in themſelves, are grown too ſtrong for the <hi>King of Terrors,</hi> and much more for all petty Kings or Rulers on earth, that muſt yeeld to him.</p>
            <p>You are the <hi>regenerate</hi> Generation of <hi>juſt</hi> and <hi>upright</hi> ones, who have dayes and nights in priſons, holes, or corners, made it your work to become true learners of your gentle Lord and Maſter, to be <hi>meek and lowly,</hi> and by bearing his eaſie <hi>Yoke,</hi> of ſelf-denying love, are become bound in Spirit, not to avoid, but freely embrace all others; bending your minds to that <hi>holy ſtillneſs</hi> and ſilence, wherein ye are inſtructed to <hi>commune with your own hearts,</hi> and by doing ſo have eſcaped the flattering in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticements of the <hi>ſtrange woman, whoſe wayes are moveable</hi> to hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the ſimple in heart from <hi>pondering the path of Life:</hi> and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving countermin'd the ſubtil evil one in all his ſecret coverts of the ſelf-loving <hi>nature,</hi> and by renouncing all hidden leagues with the luſtful <hi>bondage of corruption,</hi> have let the immortal oppreſſed ſeed of God in you <hi>go free;</hi> Behold, even in that true freedom of the <hi>Son, you are become free indeed.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Free from all <hi>creature-intanglements,</hi> that would engage and anticipate your affections, and hinder your minds from making thoſe continual <hi>aſcents,</hi> and <hi>deſcents,</hi> which only concern the <hi>will</hi> and <hi>work</hi> of your heavenly Father. <hi>Free</hi> I ſay to follow the holy innocent, patient <hi>Lamb of God whereſoever he goes,</hi> even into thoſe untrodden pathes of <hi>daily death to eternal Life,</hi> which un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crucified fleſh may boggle at and account uneaſie: and all this
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:33971:4"/>
to no other end, than that by <hi>ſtraitning</hi> your ſelves by this fiery <hi>Baptiſm,</hi> and <hi>contracting</hi> your ſelves within the narrow gate of <hi>ſelf-denial,</hi> your hearts and ſoules may become the more inlarg'd in <hi>univerſal love</hi> to God, and <hi>good will to men,</hi> in true bowels of pity, mourning over the poor <hi>blind</hi> and their <hi>blind-leaders;</hi> as alſo willing to direct them both in all humility, to him that is ready to <hi>lead them</hi> as he hath you, <hi>by a way unknown</hi> till it be tried, and telling them with a brotherly kind of tenderneſs, that this <hi>glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous liberty</hi> wherein you are <hi>new made</hi> and <hi>free-born,</hi> Chriſt hath purchaſed and obtained for them alſo, if they will but accept it in his <hi>obedience.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>O ye <hi>Free-born Citizens of the New-Jeruſalem,</hi> your time is come to <hi>awake and come out of the duſt,</hi> where ye have lain long <hi>among the pots; put on your beautiful garments of praiſe,</hi> lay aſide your <hi>ſack-cloth</hi> O ye <hi>ſlain,</hi> but now <hi>living Witneſſes</hi> of Chriſt, who is the Truth and Life, and in this <hi>cloud</hi> that now ariſes of earth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly trouble coming upon all Nations and Countries, <hi>previous</hi> to the much longer calme and quiet which will follow, <hi>aſcend</hi> into the higheſt heavenly converſation while your enemies ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold you, yea, aſcend ſo as to deſcend no more, but for his ſake whoſe voice draws and calls you up <hi>thither,</hi> even <hi>Chriſt who is your Life,</hi> who as he appears in you, ſo will you with him, not in a vain, but real <hi>glory,</hi> even that <hi>glory</hi> upon which there is a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence both night and day; a defence of <hi>Lambes</hi> from <hi>Wolves,</hi> but offenſive to none, ſave onely ſuch as in ſtead of yeelding or caſting themſelves into that gentle, warming, and nouriſhing heat of Divine <hi>Love,</hi> which ſhould <hi>cleanſe and purify</hi> them from enmity and all other <hi>uncleanneſs,</hi> do but kindle a <hi>fire</hi> of luſtful wrath to devour their own ſoules, whereby they intended to conſume others.</p>
            <p>It hath been the great joy of preſent and paſt ages to ſuch, as by <hi>Faith,</hi> which is <hi>the evidence of things not ſeen</hi> (by the carnal eye or darkened underſtanding) could take a pleaſing proſpect of the <hi>New-creation-glory,</hi> as well as the <hi>reſtitution</hi> of the old be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it <hi>is to paſſe away,</hi> the <hi>myſtery</hi> whereof hath been alwaies <hi>hid from the wiſe and prudent,</hi> in Chriſt, who <hi>reveals</hi> himſelf to <hi>babe</hi> and <hi>ſucklings:</hi> Theſe things were beautiful and lovely in their <hi>root,</hi> but much more as they grow manifeſt in the <hi>branch of righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs,</hi> the very <hi>leaves</hi> of which ſhall <hi>heal the Nations,</hi> and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:33971:5"/>
all that are not incurable by reaſon of their fixt and irre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>concileable enmity againſt him, that is <hi>unchangable</hi> in his love and goodneſs: whereby a good <hi>time of refreſhing</hi> ſhall come now, no leſs to anſwer the longing expectance of the weary oppreſſed <hi>Creature,</hi> which remaines as yet <hi>ſubject</hi> (though not willingly) <hi>to bondage,</hi> then to raiſe and heighten the ſpiritual glory of ſuch as are <hi>renewed in the ſpirit of their minds; an earneſt of which re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demption,</hi> both general and ſpecial, all you have received, who have willingly quit what is <hi>old,</hi> and are contented it ſhould paſs away, that you might be made <hi>new</hi> to all things, and <hi>all things new to you</hi> both within and without you.</p>
            <p>O you to whom this <hi>changable world</hi> yeelds no content in its moſt alluring ſmiles or flatteries, nor terrour in its frowns, but have ſtill amidſt all its variety, ſought for the <hi>one true unchangable</hi> being, and an <hi>unchangable union</hi> with it; behold now all <hi>vails</hi> and <hi>coverings</hi> will be <hi>worn away,</hi> the <hi>ſhadows muſt fly</hi> apace, and the true <hi>ſubſtance</hi> appear, ſo <hi>as every eye ſhall ſee him,</hi> though at pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent he comes in clouds, even he whom the <hi>earthly kindreds,</hi> and breed of but ſeeming Saints and ſinners, have <hi>pierced;</hi> but they <hi>ſhall mourn becauſe of him,</hi> who ſhall be <hi>admired in all</hi> them that wait for and <hi>believe in him.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The force of <hi>Armes nor Armies,</hi> nor yet the <hi>carnal Policy</hi> or <hi>Grandure</hi> of this world can any longer withſtand that work, which now is to be wrought in the fight of all <hi>nations, not by might nor by power, but by the ſpirit of the Lord;</hi> which work is neither outward or inward ſingly, but both, even the one as well as the other, and therefore, room no further remains for craft or ſubtilty to <hi>practiſe</hi> and <hi>proſper; no inchantments againſt Jacob, nor divination againſt Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rael</hi> ſhall hurt the remnant that is <hi>redeemed from the earth, &amp; un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>defiled in the way; but the wicked ſhall be inſnared in the work of his own hands,</hi> and the righteous whom they plot againſt, even by ſtanding ſtill in pure obedience to the will of God, abſtracted from all ſelf-motions or deſires, ſhall <hi>ſee the ſalvation of the Lord.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Yea the Nations ſhall ſee it, and a meer <hi>man ſhall ſay, there is a reward for the righteous, verily he is a God that judgeth in the earth.</hi> But the Eagle-eyed Saints of the moſt High God, that do already ſee beyond all vails and coverings that are not of the Spirit, can now ſay that <hi>Babylon is fallen,</hi> yea the Towers thereof are now faln, <hi>ſhe is ſunk as a milſtone in the Sea,</hi> ſhe ſhall riſe no
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:33971:5"/>
more; even that <hi>Scarlet-coloured Whore</hi> that hath for ſo many ages together, intoxicated <hi>the Kings of the Earth with her filthy Cup of Fornication,</hi> and as well her Supporters, as her Merchants that were ſupported by her, are both ready to cry, <hi>Alas, alas,</hi> and <hi>ſtand aloof off from her,</hi> not daring, if deſiring to give her any help, or ſhew her any kindneſs or pity.</p>
            <p>'Tis <hi>blood</hi> of Saints ſhe hath long had, and <hi>blood ſhe ſhall have now to drink</hi> her ſelf, <hi>for ſhe is worthy,</hi> and that <hi>doubly filled unto her</hi> by ſuch as are taught of God to <hi>ſhake their hands from holding her bribes,</hi> whether Gold or Silver, or any of her carnal delicacies, pleaſures or preferments; but ſhall <hi>execute the Vengeance written,</hi> in that holy zeal for Gods Houſe againſt her <hi>falſe Temple-worſhips,</hi> that it ſhall even <hi>eat them up</hi> that do it, and cauſe them to ceaſe from a deſire of being, but in the Will of him that calls to work, and gathers <hi>his ſanctified ones together</hi> from all quarters and corners, whither the winds of ſtrife, and diſſention of Sects and Parties hath carried them; for whoſe ſake, the many <hi>Waters,</hi> or multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tudes of People and Nations <hi>ſhall</hi> quickly <hi>divide and ſtand upon heaps, for the Ranſomed to paſs thorow</hi> the tumult and noiſe thereof, into that holy ſtilneſs and reſt, both inward and outward, wherein they may lie down quietly, &amp; <hi>none ſhall be able to make them afraid.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nor ſhall the ſingle work of Vengeance upon the ſeed of Enmi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty be all that Chriſt hath now to do in the world, but his holy meek ones that have been his faithful ſervants in giving <hi>the word of their Teſtimony, crying aloud, and not ſparing</hi> great or ſmall, and therein have walked <hi>with</hi> God (not <hi>before</hi> him in the haſty wrath of man, nor ſtaid behind him or tarried longer in a ſevere mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtration, than to ſee <hi>Juſtice and Mercy kiſs each other</hi>) ſuch I ſay ſhall be taken on, and <hi>tranſlated</hi> to the more higher or <hi>more ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent way</hi> of love to Righteouſneſs, Truth and <hi>Peace that paſſes underſtanding,</hi> and being enabled to <hi>ſing the ſong of Moſes, and of the Lamb,</hi> ſhall ceaſe to ſtrive any longer with men in an out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward warfare, as having obtained the <hi>victory over the Accuſer</hi> or evil-one within them; but in ſtead of maintaining Feuds and marks of diſtinction or enmity, ſhall imitate the <hi>good Samaritan,</hi> in pouring <hi>Wine and Oyl into the wounds</hi> of any that refuſe not to be healed: being big with deſire to ſee all as intire by <hi>love,</hi> as they themſelves are by <hi>patience,</hi> that the very whole race of mankind, if it were poſſible, might joyn with them in ſinging
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:33971:6"/>
the new Goſpel-Song of praiſe; <hi>Glory to God in the higheſt, peace on earth, and good will towards men.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>For as <hi>all fleſh is graſs, and the glory of man,</hi> conſiſting in the wiſdom of words or thoughts, <hi>but as the flower of graſs,</hi> the one <hi>withers</hi> and the other <hi>fades,</hi> ſo <hi>the living word of God,</hi> that lies deeper in the heart than both the other, <hi>abides for ever;</hi> and they whoſe union is perfect therewith, cannot but deſire it for all elſe, even in his will and love that is the <hi>Saviour</hi> of the world, and <hi>will have all men to be ſaved, and come to the knowledge of the truth;</hi> ſo are they the true publiſhers or preachers in good works as well as words, of the everlaſting Goſpel <hi>to all Nations,</hi> who ere long ſhall bring all their honour to the <hi>Lamb,</hi> and the very wealth or <hi>forces of the Gentiles,</hi> muſt come freely to Chriſt's Church and followers.</p>
            <p>O ye <hi>followers of the Lamb whitherſoever he goes,</hi> who have <hi>gird<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed up the loines of your mind,</hi> in true ſobriety and <hi>hope to the end</hi> of all things which is at hand; haſten to come forth of all <hi>Sects</hi> and <hi>Parties,</hi> wherein the cunning adverſary hath <hi>beguiled</hi> and <hi>de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained</hi> you, tempting to retain unbrotherly diſtinctions between <hi>members of the ſame Body,</hi> which is but one, whoſe <hi>hope</hi> alſo, <hi>cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, Lord, faith, baptiſm is</hi> but <hi>one.</hi> Live therefore as if ye were all <hi>of him,</hi> and he all <hi>to you,</hi> as well as <hi>in all</hi> elſe beſide you, though ſome indeed are <hi>worthy</hi> but of ſingle, as others are of double <hi>honour:</hi> Joyn ye hands and hearts, to countermine the Seducer, and at once convince the world whoſe diſciples you are by <hi>loving one another.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Come ye off with one conſent out of all particular by-wayes or forms, to the <hi>power</hi> and <hi>life,</hi> even the true <hi>end of the Command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> which <hi>is charity out of a pure heart, and of a good conſcience, and of faith unfained:</hi> ye have too long <hi>ſown the</hi> changeable <hi>wind</hi> of ſtrife and contention among your ſelves, and <hi>reapt the whirl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wind</hi> of fierceneſs and cruelty one upon another; learn ye at laſt to <hi>ſowe beſides all waters,</hi> or people, and ſo ſend forth your affecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons like <hi>the feet of the Oxe</hi> for labour, <hi>and the Aſſe</hi> for bearing burdens; learn, oh diligently learn to preach the <hi>everlaſting Goſpel</hi> to all Nations, in fewer words and better works of <hi>uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal love,</hi> and brotherly kindneſs, then the meer hireling could ever practiſe.</p>
            <p>'Tis but a little, yea very <hi>little while, and he that ſhall come will
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:33971:6"/>
come and will not tarry,</hi> who hath already broken down the <hi>partiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on wall</hi> between God and man, between man and man, between Jew and Gentile, and hath by his own pretious blood, <hi>made of one blood all Nations, who are his off-ſpring,</hi> before the whotiſh ſpirit of this world claimes them, and a diviſion of them, as the falſe Mother did of the child unto <hi>Solomon:</hi> behold <hi>a greater than Solomon,</hi> hath bounded all habitations, to the end that none might invade or violate others, or cover the inlargement of their own dominion: <hi>The earth is the Lord's</hi> not <hi>ours,</hi> but as we are <hi>his,</hi> and being ſo, <hi>all things are ours,</hi> and become ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject to us, without force or ſtriving.</p>
            <p>When we <hi>dwell in love, we dwell in God, for God is love,</hi> that's his <hi>white Name</hi> and <hi>pure Nature,</hi> whereby we are to <hi>know him,</hi> as alſo <hi>to be known of him,</hi> and each to other, whether among <hi>bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren</hi> or <hi>ſtrangers,</hi> for this being in the heart, <hi>ſtrife of tongues,</hi> and <hi>diviſion of language</hi> will abate quickly.</p>
            <p>This is that which makes moſt deſireable, not the <hi>upper</hi> but the lower <hi>ſeat,</hi> whether at the <hi>feaſt of fat things,</hi> which Chriſt makes, or in the <hi>Synagogue</hi> which conſiſts not of Satan's followers, who are the outward Jewes onely, but <hi>inward</hi> ones, <hi>circumciſed in heart,</hi> ſeeking their praiſe <hi>not of men but God, who ſees in ſecret,</hi> but <hi>rewards openly,</hi> but does firſt train up his ſons and daughters in the <hi>form of ſervants,</hi> before he makes them <hi>Lords of all.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The greateſt favourites to <hi>the King of kings,</hi> ſubject their <hi>in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> man to him onely, but their <hi>outward</hi> to every one that treads upon and bruiſes it, by which ſuffering and no otherwiſe, they come to reign, in this manner, by conviction, taking them <hi>captive</hi> whoſe <hi>captives</hi> they were: As their Captain leads, ſo do they follow, under his <hi>skirt</hi> and <hi>banner</hi> diſplay'd, <hi>the motto</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, as it was written in <hi>his blood,</hi> ſo are they content it ſhould be <hi>in their own,</hi> viz. <hi>Love your Enemies.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Oh what pen can write, or tongue expreſſe the tranſcendent joy, the ſurpaſſing glory of ſuch <hi>conqueſts,</hi> that are begun in <hi>ſelf-hatred,</hi> &amp; conclude in <hi>univerſal love</hi> to the whole <hi>Creation of God!</hi> in which kind of <hi>aſcent</hi> we gain, as by <hi>deſcent</hi> into the luſt we loſt the true <hi>dominion;</hi> and as the <hi>true knowledge</hi> failed in the one, and the <hi>falſe or deceitful</hi> ſpread it ſelf in ſtead thereof, as a paint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed face or <hi>covering over all fleſh;</hi> ſo in the other, will all falſe <hi>vails</hi> vaniſh or wear away, and the <hi>true real knowledge of the glory of
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:33971:7"/>
the Lord, cover the earth as the waters cover the ſea:</hi> yea, <hi>new Names</hi> will be given to all things when they become <hi>new,</hi> and their <hi>natures intuitively known</hi> by this <hi>redemption,</hi> after their long burial and obſcurity in or by the <hi>bondage of corruption.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>What <hi>ſtrength, power,</hi> or <hi>wiſdom</hi> is of value, that ſprings not to a <hi>new Life,</hi> or appearance by <hi>death of the old?</hi> and that which does, what can maſter it? being too <hi>ſtrong for death,</hi> it <hi>prevailes againſt the very gates of hell:</hi> and who would not love <hi>death</hi> for the <hi>reſurrections</hi> ſake to a <hi>new life,</hi> wherein the <hi>clog of fleſh and blood</hi> that can never <hi>enter,</hi> much leſs <hi>inherit the kingdom</hi> that con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſts in <hi>righteouſneſs, peace and joy,</hi> is wholly put off, whereby the ſoul becomes <hi>clothed upon</hi> with a <hi>new ſpiritual houſe from above,</hi> that is not too ſtrait, but large enough for entertainment, (and that <hi>not for a night as a wayfaring-man,</hi> but even perpetual) to <hi>the King of Glory.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Let us therefore bid farewel to the <hi>old houſe of clay</hi> and all its ſenſual ſupporters; <hi>the fools Paradiſe of full barns, and earthly plenty,</hi> muſt never bend the mind to any longer lingrings or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lays in this <hi>Sodomitical old world;</hi> the <hi>bread of a Fathers houſe</hi> is now a loud call from <hi>husky</hi> vanities, the continued diverſion whereof cannot but be very burdenſom to any ſoul that hath fed at <hi>wiſdoms table,</hi> and taſted her <hi>mingled wine of the kingdom, that glads the heart both of God and man.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>An End</hi> is now proclaimed <hi>of all perfection under the Sun,</hi> and nothing is now of value but that <hi>Commandment,</hi> and keeping it, <hi>which is exceeding broad;</hi> of no leſs breadth than between <hi>Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven and Earth;</hi> for 'tis the ſeed of <hi>Jacob's Ladder</hi> that reaches both, and not onely gives <hi>light,</hi> but <hi>ſtrength</hi> alſo in the <hi>angelical</hi> life, <hi>to aſcend</hi> by Faith, <hi>and deſcend</hi> by Love even at pleaſure.</p>
            <p>This <hi>New Commandment</hi> of Love is the <hi>ſtill voice</hi> of the great <hi>Shepherd,</hi> whoſe <hi>ſheep hear him,</hi> and know it from the loud <hi>voice of a ſtranger,</hi> and by following him that loves them, they cannot only go <hi>in,</hi> but <hi>out</hi> alſo, and <hi>find paſture.</hi> They know their time to <hi>retire,</hi> as alſo to <hi>go forth,</hi> and in both, they deſire to honour, ſerve, and pleaſe him, not themſelves, for 'tis their <hi>meat and drink to do his will,</hi> but not their own.</p>
            <p>O ye true <hi>ſelf-denying, crucified,</hi> and (in ſpirit) already <hi>riſen</hi> Chriſtians, bear with the fond expreſſions of a Brother, whoſe <hi>bonds</hi> are grown <hi>eaſie</hi> with <hi>wearing,</hi> who hath had his <hi>mid-night
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:33971:7"/>
ſighs and ſongs,</hi> in ſome hope that the fear of death and hell are conquered by an acquaintance with that love which can viſit both without danger, even in that life, which can abide <hi>devouring fire, and dwell with everlaſting burnings.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Where is it that he would not go to meet the true <hi>fraternity</hi> folded up together <hi>in the unity of the ſpirit,</hi> even the <hi>bond</hi> of laſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>peace</hi> and love, married or joyned to <hi>Chriſt</hi> their <hi>head</hi> and <hi>husband,</hi> who is <hi>Lord of all,</hi> whether <hi>male or female, bond or free?</hi> yea thrice happy and worthy are all ye to be ſought out, who in pure <hi>chaſtity</hi> have kept the <hi>bed undefiled</hi> during the night of <hi>apoſtacy,</hi> wherein the <hi>adulterers</hi> and <hi>adultereſſes of this world,</hi> either by frowns or flatteries have too much prevailed to ſeduce or affright <hi>the unſtable.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>What ſhould hinder <hi>harmony of ſpirits,</hi> where a <hi>fellowſhip in ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferings</hi> is freely own'd, even with <hi>ſtrong &amp; weak</hi> for his ſake whoſe divine love makes us <hi>debtors to the wiſe and unwiſe,</hi> and as ready to ſhare the <hi>penny</hi> to him that comes in at the <hi>eleventh</hi> or <hi>laſt hour,</hi> as that came at <hi>the first</hi> of the <hi>Lamb's warfare;</hi> this not being the day of vain-glorying, or ſelf-arrogance, to any that have led or born the <hi>brunt</hi> either in <hi>doing</hi> or <hi>ſuffering,</hi> ſince the pride of the <hi>one</hi> is as much accurſed as of the <hi>other;</hi> nay, if any <hi>glorying</hi> be at all, let it be <hi>in the Croſs, whereby the world,</hi> and all its honour or eſteem <hi>is crucified to us, and we to it;</hi> but <hi>if any will be greatest, let him be the miniſter;</hi> or he that would <hi>be</hi> accounted <hi>chief,</hi> for any hazard, travel, or hardſhip, performed or undergone without fainting or reluctancy, <hi>let him be the ſervant of all;</hi> deſire of <hi>Lordſhip</hi> or <hi>Dominion,</hi> is as little comely in the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> as in the <hi>Gentile world;</hi> and as its exerciſe is uneaſie to be born by <hi>Saints</hi> from <hi>Sinners,</hi> ſo no leſs by <hi>Sinners</hi> from <hi>Saints,</hi> but leaſt of all <hi>by Saints</hi> over each other, unleſs it be in that <hi>abiding Love,</hi> that refuſes to rule but in <hi>form of a fervant,</hi> and even <hi>hides</hi> it ſelf <hi>with Chriſt in God</hi> from a worldly <hi>kingdom.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The true <hi>Nobility</hi> by <hi>heavenly</hi> birth and breeding in <hi>Christ's School</hi> of <hi>long-ſuffering</hi> and <hi>fiery tryals,</hi> appears moſt by ſtooping <hi>low,</hi> not climbing on <hi>high,</hi> which is the property of the <hi>Thief</hi> that would be <hi>robbing</hi> both God and man of their due: for, as Love only that can bear <hi>ſubjection</hi> is moſt fit to <hi>reign,</hi> ſo doth it ſhew it ſelf by <hi>deſcending firſt,</hi> yea, below it ſelf, into that Life which muſt period and conclude, before it aſcends where it was, or
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:33971:8"/>
higher than at firſt. But why need words to multiply? though <hi>the Lord hath been forſaken and his holy Mountain</hi> (where is no divi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding or deſtroying) <hi>forgotten</hi> by ſome that <hi>prepare a Table for this or that Troop, and furniſh the drink-offering to that number;</hi> yet behold they are now <hi>new-born,</hi> that could freely traverſe the world, to ſeek unity with <hi>Indians, Barbarians, Turks, Jews</hi> (ſo called) and <hi>Papiſts</hi> as well as <hi>Proteſtants</hi> of all ſorts and ſizes.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nity,</hi> I ſay, <hi>in Spirit,</hi> not of this world, or the god thereof, even the <hi>falſe deceiver</hi> (that maintains his wicked Principality in the hearts of men by his engine of the ſelfiſh nature) but of the true holy One, that taſts death <hi>in every man,</hi> as well as <hi>for</hi> him, and yet ſees <hi>no corruption;</hi> whoſe <hi>light ſhines</hi> in the very <hi>darkeſt</hi> of mankind, though they <hi>comprehend it not;</hi> but when that Light, which is the ſame alſo of them that <hi>love</hi> and <hi>live</hi> in it, ſhines by <hi>good works,</hi> as it ought, <hi>before</hi> meer <hi>men,</hi> that as yet remain in <hi>darkneſs,</hi> then they may be induc'd to <hi>glorifie</hi> the heavenly <hi>Father of Spirits,</hi> and <hi>Lights</hi> of all degrees or meaſures, as well that <hi>rule by night</hi> as <hi>by day,</hi> or of <hi>ſeven dayes</hi> together gathered into the glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of one.</p>
            <p>'Tis love, even <hi>love univerſal</hi> that hath imbreathed, and its beau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty inamoured the ſoules of ſome that are but <hi>few</hi> of <hi>many,</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by they do as it were <hi>burn</hi> with holy deſires to live in union with all mankind, yea with the whole Creation, and not an <hi>Oxe</hi> or an <hi>Aſſe,</hi> or any other Creature, that <hi>groanes and travels together in pain till now,</hi> but as it <hi>waits for,</hi> ſo it rejoyces in, this <hi>glorious liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the ſons of God,</hi> who will ere long be better known among the ſons of men than heretofore, even by <hi>going forth,</hi> and <hi>growing up as Calves of the ſtall,</hi> not to be markt out for ſlaughter as they have been, but by <hi>treading down the wicked</hi> things and perſons <hi>like aſhes under the ſoales of their feet,</hi> when <hi>the Lord ſhall by fire and his</hi> ſpiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual <hi>ſword plead with all fleſh, and the ſlain of the Lord,</hi> rather then of his People, in whom he ſhall be admired, <hi>will be very many;</hi> becauſe now the weapons of the Saints <hi>warfare</hi> will appear daily <hi>not carnal,</hi> but more and more <hi>ſpiritual,</hi> inabling them to ſingle out and encounter thoſe <hi>ſpiritual wickedneſſes in the high places</hi> of their own hearts and others, thereby bringing <hi>down the mighty from their ſeats, and exalting them that are of low degree;</hi> and all this with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any deſtroying in <hi>that holy mountain of God</hi> where they con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe, which in this reſpect <hi>is lifted up above all others,</hi> and will ſuddenly <hi>fill the whole earth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:33971:8"/>O ye <hi>Victorious Army of the Lamb,</hi> who on <hi>white horſes,</hi> as Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blems of <hi>Peace and Love,</hi> and <hi>in linnen white and clean,</hi> (which betokens the innocence and <hi>righteouſneſſes of Saints</hi>) have follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him that is now <hi>gone forth conquering and to conquer;</hi> glorious is and will be the triumph, by the <hi>death of the Croſs,</hi> over all <hi>cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ated excellencies,</hi> as well as <hi>impure defilements,</hi> by abandoning the <hi>adultrous ſpirit of this world:</hi> O ye that witneſs the <hi>conqueſt of de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire</hi> to any <hi>carnal pleaſure,</hi> which tends but to <hi>ſtupifie</hi> the <hi>immor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal ſoul</hi> of man, and bring it into the <hi>ſleeps</hi> or ſlumbers <hi>of eternal death;</hi> great is your wiſdom in determining <hi>to know nothing but Chriſt and him crucified,</hi> and in ſtanding alwayes delivered up to <hi>death for Jeſus ſake, that the life of Chriſt might the more be manifeſt in your mortal fleſh;</hi> great is your power and authority in the world, as you appear already <hi>riſen with Chriſt, by ſeeking thoſe things that are above;</hi> as ye are living witneſſes of the <hi>firſt Reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection</hi> myſtical, ſo you tell the world that the <hi>literal</hi> is not far off: and therefore, what <hi>Priſons or Inquiſitions</hi> can longer hold you, what outward <hi>Chains</hi> can bind you that are inwardly free? <hi>who is it that will harm you, that are followers of good,</hi> but eſchew the evil in every appearance?</p>
            <p>O ye that have choſen the moſt <hi>ſolitary paths</hi> that an earthly <hi>pilgrimage</hi> could yeeld, therein to <hi>meet your Beloved, whoſe love is better than wine,</hi> that does but refreſh and exhilerate for a ſeaſon, and then the natural man that is ſerved, becomes as heavy as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore 'twas taſted, but the pleaſure of <hi>your love and eſpouſals</hi> with the Lamb knows <hi>no end,</hi> it grows in you, and you in it, with ſuch <hi>divine increaſes,</hi> till it ſwallowes up words and thoughts, as thoſe <hi>narrow medium's</hi> which are far below, and too ſtrait for the expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of that loving life which is incapeable of any confinement, but enlarges it ſelf freely in and unto all that entertain it.</p>
            <p>You that have conquered <hi>the great and laſt enemy,</hi> and that by yeelding <hi>daily</hi> to it; what other enemies, but either are or <hi>will be at peace with you?</hi> becauſe you fear not <hi>them,</hi> but love and fear <hi>him</hi> that commands all <hi>hearts and hands;</hi> yea, the very ſtones of the ſtreet, and beaſts of the field <hi>will be in league with you,</hi> not to <hi>offend</hi> but <hi>defend you;</hi> though becauſe your <hi>munition of rocks,</hi> and <hi>wall of fire</hi> is never wanting, all other help from without is whol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly needleſs, and ſuch as offer it, do rather expreſs their own love than your deſire of any <hi>guard</hi> or <hi>regard,</hi> but what alwayes comes from <hi>heaven before you call or ask it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:33971:9"/>Your <hi>Wiſdom is from above;</hi> What <hi>Serpent</hi> can <hi>beguile</hi> you? you are <hi>redeemed</hi> from the Power of all things <hi>below;</hi> What <hi>Scorpion</hi> or <hi>deadly Poyſon can hurt you?</hi> ye are paſt the <hi>Fear of Pain,</hi> no Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant can torment you; yea, you have paſt thorow <hi>Sorrows, Sighs,</hi> and <hi>Tears</hi> beyond them, you are neither to be <hi>exalted</hi> or <hi>abaſed</hi> by any thing which <hi>Fleſh can give or take;</hi> your <hi>Life, Peace</hi> and <hi>Joy is endleſs,</hi> becauſe your <hi>Love is ſtronger than Death.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Who will not bend or yield to you, and <hi>take hold of your skirts,</hi> O ye <hi>inward Jews, circumciſed in heart,</hi> and be <hi>called</hi> by your <hi>New-name?</hi> for all your Names are given by Him, whoſe Name is <hi>One,</hi> that <hi>no man knows but he that hath it;</hi> Your <hi>Language one,</hi> and not divided; Your <hi>Church but one,</hi> and not rent in Schiſms, Sects or <hi>Diviſions;</hi> And therefore not <hi>Carnal,</hi> but Spiritual, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>known, <hi>inviſible</hi> to the <hi>World,</hi> but well <hi>known</hi> to <hi>Chriſt</hi> your Head, and one another.</p>
            <p>O ye that admit no <hi>Buyers or Sellers in your inner Man,</hi> the <hi>Lord's Temple,</hi> but are freed from Cares and Cumbers of this World, having ſold all your Poſſeſſions <hi>perſonal,</hi> to gain the <hi>real;</hi> and therefore have not <hi>ſpent your Money for that which is not Bread,</hi> and does not ſatisfie, but <hi>laid it</hi> all <hi>down</hi> at the <hi>great Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles feet,</hi> with a free willing mind, to quit all ſingle ſelfiſh pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perty that is from beneath, for that univerſal equal Liberty that is from above; and as well to <hi>diſtribute</hi> or <hi>communicate</hi> your Wealth of <hi>good Works</hi> to an <hi>Enemy</hi> or poor <hi>Stranger,</hi> as unto a <hi>Friend</hi> or <hi>Brother:</hi> What man or ſort of men under the Sun, when they ſee you walk by this <hi>Principle,</hi> but will deſire your <hi>ru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling with,</hi> if not <hi>over</hi> them? You are the <hi>Governours of</hi> Judah <hi>that rule with God,</hi> becauſe God rules <hi>in</hi> you, and alwayes checks the entrance of any other, that is ſtrange or forreign, to his All-pure impartial Spirit; you that have learn'd of <hi>Shiloh the proſper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er,</hi> to <hi>heal Breaches,</hi> and <hi>reſtore Paths</hi> to <hi>dwell in;</hi> What People, Nation or Language will not ask your Help to <hi>new lay their Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dations,</hi> renew their <hi>Land-marks,</hi> to re-build the <hi>waſt Places, and Deſolations of many Generations?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>All Government in things <hi>ſpiritual</hi> you yield <hi>to Chriſt</hi> onely in things <hi>temporal,</hi> to <hi>Him</hi> and <hi>the Nations,</hi> whereof he is as well <hi>King</hi> as <hi>of Saints;</hi> yea, <hi>the Heathen are his Inheritance,</hi> and <hi>the utmoſt parts of the Earth are his Poſſeſſion.</hi> You are ſo far from that degenerous practice of <hi>Plotting</hi> either by <hi>fraud</hi> or <hi>force,</hi>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:33971:9"/>
againſt the Life of <hi>Prince</hi> or <hi>Peaſant,</hi> that you follow his ſteps <hi>that ſaves the Life both of man and Beaſt;</hi> yea, abhorring the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Thoughts of any Contrivance, to <hi>impoſe</hi> the moſt apparent Good againſt, or <hi>without Conſent</hi> of ſuch, for whom it is pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; and becauſe you are already <hi>free in Chriſt's Freedom,</hi> you chooſe to dye rather than be <hi>impoſed upon by your own Conſent,</hi> to derogate from Him who hath made you <hi>free indeed.</hi> In this Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit you ſtand alwayes armed with the <hi>Armour of Light and Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs</hi> for all eſſayes, whether to <hi>do</hi> what is <hi>lawful,</hi> or ſuffer what the Captain of your Salvation determins to be <hi>expedient</hi> for your nearer Fellowſhip with him: You are linked faſt together in a <hi>holy Band of Union,</hi> which is inward <hi>Brotherly-love,</hi> rather than any outward <hi>Confederacies,</hi> and by being continually in the pure Simplicity, and keeping <hi>a good Conſcience towards God and all men,</hi> you cannot but carry all things of Satans Work down before you, not ſo much by force as by conviction, breaking in pieces all <hi>Leagues that are made with Death or Hell,</hi> and ſuch as would maintain them; refuſing <hi>Peace</hi> while and whereſoever <hi>the Whoredoms and Witchcrafts of the well</hi> or <hi>ill-favoured Harlot remain,</hi> but <hi>ſeeking it with all men,</hi> even of all degrees, <hi>High and Low, Rich and Poor;</hi> for ye deny Leagues of Amity with no Perſon or Nation, that will admit <hi>the King of Peace</hi> to reign <hi>in</hi> or <hi>over</hi> them, although his Titles, <hi>(Authority and Power)</hi> given him <hi>by the Father,</hi> and his <hi>Name above other Names,</hi> be not in that manner or Scripture-language known, as to your ſelves.</p>
            <p>You know <hi>who</hi> it is that <hi>hath made you to differ From</hi> other men; and therefore for his ſake only (and never elſe) you differ <hi>With</hi> them: but becauſe <hi>God in Chriſt is</hi> already <hi>reconciled to the world,</hi> your great Work is to reconcile the <hi>world</hi> to <hi>God,</hi> and as you find that Difference ended, you let fall all others; yea, rather than you can <hi>ſtrive</hi> or contend, that are <hi>the Lord's Servants,</hi> you ſerve them that call you <hi>Maſters,</hi> not deſiring ſo much to <hi>rule with,</hi> or <hi>over</hi> Princes, as to <hi>ſub-ſerve</hi> the meaneſt of their Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects; for you count it no honour to ſee heads <hi>bare,</hi> or knees <hi>bowed</hi> to you, but <hi>to go about doing good,</hi> and yet obſcuring your ſelves from them to whom you are as <hi>Benefactors,</hi> treading his ſteps that did ſo, and who long ſince <hi>rejoyced in the habitable Parts of God's Earth, whoſe delights were with the ſons of men;</hi> And therefore while many that talk and pretend much of common
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:33971:10"/>
good, but do indeed <hi>ſeek their own more than the things of Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> you do even <hi>naturally care for the State of others,</hi> and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy your ſelves without hope of any Reward, but in the <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of God,</hi> to <hi>heal the Sick, relieve the Poor,</hi> end Quarrels or Contentions, <hi>make Enemies Friends, and convert Souls</hi> to him, that hath <hi>offered himſelf as a Ranſom for, and a Saviour unto all,</hi> and yet <hi>came to call not the Righteous, but Sinners to Repentance.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>O ye <hi>living Witneſſes of Chriſt's Kingdom,</hi> and Inſtruments in his hand to reduce the <hi>Kingdoms of this World</hi> in quiet free Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection to him, not by the <hi>Battle or confuſed Noiſe of the Warri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our, and Garments roul'd in Blood, but by ſuch kind of burnings and fiery Tryals,</hi> as will neither mix and confound, or conſume the precious with the vile, but only ſeparate each from other, and leave both to him that <hi>iudgeth righteouſly:</hi> What can hinder you from <hi>taking the Kingdom?</hi> for unto you <hi>Saints of the Moſt High God,</hi> is it given, and <hi>greatneſs of the Dominion under the whole Heaven;</hi> take it <hi>within</hi> and <hi>cover</hi> your ſelves, and all <hi>with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out</hi> will quickly appear given unto you; take it within <hi>by force againſt your ſelves,</hi> and all without ſhall be given you by <hi>conſent;</hi> for when you are <hi>not your own, all is yours,</hi> becauſe <hi>you are Chriſt's, and Chriſt is God's.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Behold, our <hi>King of kings comes lowly,</hi> he that hath been long under, muſt now reign <hi>over</hi> all; and who will not meet Him with a <hi>Palm Branch,</hi> and cry <hi>Hoſanna to the Higheſt: He that was dead</hi> does now begin to appear <hi>riſen</hi> in his meek lamb-like <hi>holy Ones,</hi> and <hi>ſhall die no more,</hi> but be for ever <hi>admired in them,</hi> becauſe they have <hi>believed on Him,</hi> whoſe <hi>Faith</hi> will now appear not <hi>Fan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy</hi> or <hi>Notion,</hi> but the clear <hi>Evidence of things not ſeen,</hi> by ſuch as ſay they ſee more than others; the Myſtery of God that hath been declared to his Servants and Prophets will be revealed ſuddenly, becauſe well nigh <hi>finiſhed,</hi> and the <hi>ſeventh Angel</hi> is about to <hi>ſound</hi> his <hi>Trumpet;</hi> yea, <hi>the Viſion</hi> that hath been long <hi>waited for,</hi> will <hi>tarry no longer,</hi> but appear <hi>plain upon the fleſhly Tables</hi> of all <hi>pure hearts,</hi> and they that <hi>run ſo as to obtain, may read it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The high way of the upright to depart from evil,</hi> will now be free from the prevaling Power of the <hi>great Robber,</hi> and the peculiar <hi>way of holineſs</hi> ſo well known, and clear'd from <hi>ſtumbling-Blocks</hi>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:33971:10"/>
of Babels Merchants laying therein, that the pooreſt <hi>Traveller</hi> of <hi>Wayfaring-man, though a Fool</hi> for Chriſt's ſake, yet <hi>ſhall not err therein;</hi> becauſe <hi>the Anointing</hi> that inſtructs him <hi>in all things,</hi> is his inward Teacher, which being <hi>the Truth and no lye,</hi> and ſo underſtood as well as an obedience yielded thereunto, <hi>his Bread is ſure, his Waters cannot faile</hi> though his outward <hi>Teachers be removed to corners.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>crooked Wayes</hi> alſo of all humane converſe in general ſhall be made ſtreight, and the <hi>ruff Places</hi> of learning or teaching Knowledge, of any kind in particular, <hi>ſhall be made plain;</hi> for the mear <hi>Hireling</hi> and Deceiver muſt be excluded from bearing rule in all <hi>Studies, Arts,</hi> or <hi>Sciences,</hi> as well as <hi>vulgar Trades</hi> or <hi>Callings,</hi> by the coming of <hi>Elias,</hi> who is already born, that <hi>will prepare the Way of the Lord</hi> in all things and perſons, ſo as Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rightneſs, Honeſty, and that kind of Self-denying-Love, or <hi>Charity that ſeeks not its own</hi> in any thing, but the common Good of others muſt take place among the Sons of men, whoſe Dea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings each with other are to be regulated by <hi>the Lord's Standard,</hi> and <hi>Ballance of the Sanctuary;</hi> for <hi>out of</hi> Zion <hi>ſhall the Law go forth, and the Word of the Lord which will call all Nations from Jeruſalem.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Pen or Tongue of Men and Angels cannot declare the Glory of the <hi>Reſtitution of all things,</hi> to their firſt Innocence and Purity; muchleſs of that <hi>new Creation</hi> which will follow it, when the old is ſubjected by Fire to him; that as he was the firſt <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker</hi> of all in the <hi>Beginning,</hi> ſo is the <hi>New-maker</hi> of all in the <hi>End,</hi> for <hi>He is the ſame yeſterday, to day and for ever;</hi> but before <hi>that paſſes away</hi> which is not perpetual or <hi>abidiag,</hi> his Soveraign Power will appear in <hi>ſaving</hi> it <hi>to the uttermoſt,</hi> whereof 'tis capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble; and thereby let the more numerous part of <hi>Mankind</hi> know ſomething of an <hi>earthly happineſs,</hi> that have refuſed the <hi>heavenly,</hi> though they have been called to the <hi>latter,</hi> as well as have loſt (though poſſeſt of) the former; and likewiſe cauſe thoſe few to <hi>inherit Incorruption,</hi> who being <hi>choſen</hi> thereunto (in him that <hi>ſaw no corruption</hi>) have according to their good deeds done in the body, deſired their <hi>corruptible</hi> part <hi>to put it on,</hi> and their <hi>mortali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty</hi> to be <hi>ſwallowed up of</hi> immortal <hi>Life,</hi> rather than (in doing evil) of eternal <hi>Death.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An earthly (I ſay or temporal) happineſs that's real, not that
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:33971:11"/>
onely ſeems ſo, by <hi>letting looſe the ſelfiſh nature</hi> to feed upon any thing forbidden that <hi>periſheth,</hi> but by <hi>bridling</hi> it, and ſo preſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving mankind in that <hi>abſtinence</hi> and <hi>forbearance,</hi> which may pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pare them to ſuſtain that <hi>fiery tryal</hi> which the <hi>Cherubims</hi> and <hi>fla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming ſword,</hi> that is previous to the enduring ſupplies and <hi>ſubſtance that never fail,</hi> from the <hi>Tree of Life,</hi> which <hi>Chriſt</hi> is to every one that waits upon, and believeth in him.</p>
            <p>For the time is at hand when <hi>open iniquity ſhall ſtop her mouth,</hi> and <hi>wickedneſs</hi> have no longer place upon <hi>the houſe top,</hi> but be driven from <hi>corner</hi> to <hi>corner,</hi> and from one <hi>Nation</hi> to <hi>another,</hi> till at laſt it find <hi>no room in the world.</hi> But <hi>juſtice, equity, righteouſneſs, and temperance</hi> ſhall ſpread it ſelf among all people, as that <hi>com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon ſalvation of all men,</hi> which, though now the great multitudes that live more like <hi>beaſts</hi> than <hi>men,</hi> ſeem to render as a thing <hi>im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible,</hi> yet thoſe <hi>redeemed ones from the earth</hi> and among men, in whoſe <hi>mouthes is found no guile,</hi> that witneſs a life of <hi>faith,</hi> above (though not contrary to) that of <hi>reaſon</hi> and <hi>morality</hi> in the beſt of meer men, do already ſee it more than <hi>probable.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The knowledge of <hi>the Lord's glory covering the earth as waters cover the ſea,</hi> leaves no room for ignorance on the one hand, or for a falſe vain appearance of knowledge or glory on the other; but when <hi>the fear of the Lord</hi> ſhall be acknowledged as <hi>the begin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning of wiſdom</hi> by all that deſire it, not for their <hi>own ſake,</hi> but of <hi>Christ</hi> in whom the <hi>treaſure</hi> thereof <hi>is hidden,</hi> as well as for the good of their neighbour; then will men underſtand, that <hi>Wiſdom dwels with Prudence, and finds out the knowledge of witty inventions,</hi> which are to be ſubject and ſubſervient to his ends onely, that freely <hi>teaches the plow-man, and inſtructs him to diſcretion,</hi> both to <hi>ſow and reap,</hi> as well as <hi>to threſh and bruiſe the bread-corn:</hi> yea the myſteries of both Kingdoms, even of <hi>grace and nature,</hi> ſhall diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloſe themſelves, that have hither to been lock't up and hidden from the ſelf-ſeekers of both or either; ſuch myſteries as will in a manner <hi>aſtoniſh</hi> the world, and make poor <hi>brain-ſick mortals</hi> that have been long captive to <hi>vain traditions</hi> and <hi>falſe methods of knowledge</hi> of many kinds, to be <hi>like them that dream,</hi> when they ſhall after much wandring be returned to ſome clearer proſpects of what they labour after, than the <hi>wiſe</hi> and <hi>prudent</hi> could ever at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, who for building of <hi>Babels Fabricks</hi> in the <hi>Antichriſtian</hi> world, have hitherto had <hi>preheminence.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:33971:11"/>But time would fail to tell what is now in the <hi>Womb of Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence,</hi> and of that <hi>Nation</hi> which ſhall <hi>be born in a day,</hi> ready to come forth and be <hi>ſown among the people</hi> in all parts of the world, where they now ly ſcattered under various tryals, which tend but to <hi>waſh</hi> and <hi>whiten</hi> the <hi>garments</hi> of their outward converſation, whereby they may be better known, as well as by their <hi>inward principle of life, in the blood of the Lamb,</hi> to the end that by the ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour of his livery, and <hi>marks of dying</hi> or <hi>mortification</hi> in their <hi>bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies,</hi> and <hi>Chriſt</hi> being <hi>riſen in their ſpirits,</hi> they may be alſo better truſted by thoſe that have hitherto eſteemed them <hi>deceivers of men,</hi> while they have been <hi>true</hi> to him, and <hi>walk'd as he walked,</hi> who was in the world <hi>without guile,</hi> and yet reported to have <hi>had a Devil.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Oh let not my <hi>Lord Eſau</hi> be longer angry with the yonger bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, that hath <hi>ſupplanted him both of birth-right and bleſſing,</hi> ſince thereby he does but wrong his own ſoul: For <hi>Saviours muſt now come upon mount Zion to judge the mount of Eſau,</hi> but <hi>the Kingdom ſhall be the Lord's.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Even the Kingdom that is everlaſting, to which all others muſt give place, and that ſpeedily, for the Lord is nigh who <hi>hath his fan in his hand,</hi> having determined to <hi>ſift the nations with a ſeive of vanity,</hi> and to skreen the People, or ſeparate the <hi>chaffe</hi> from his <hi>true ſeed;</hi> yea it ſhall come to paſs, that <hi>in all the land ſaith the Lord, two parts therein ſhall be cut off and dye, but the third part ſhall be left therein. And I will bring the third part thorow the fire, and will refine them as ſilver is refined, and will try them as gold is tried: they ſhall call on my Name, and I will hear them, I will ſay, it is my People, and they ſhall ſay, the Lord is my God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This <hi>word of Prophecy</hi> is <hi>ſure,</hi> and will now be ſooner underſtood than in former ages, becauſe its fulfilling and accompliſhment in <hi>all Nations,</hi> but eſpecially in <hi>England,</hi> as the <hi>firſt fruits of righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs to God,</hi> and pattern to others, ſeems very near at hand.</p>
            <p>All which is witneſſed by a <hi>Priſoner of hope,</hi> that is <hi>learning</hi> of his heavenly Maſter <hi>in every ſtate to be content:</hi> and therefore to loſe his <hi>old acquaintance, kindred, country, name</hi> and <hi>nature,</hi> in ſuffering travels, by ſeeking <hi>all new,</hi> to the end he may be found no more in <hi>luſtful anger,</hi> but in <hi>love without diſſimulation,</hi> to the worſt of <hi>enemies</hi> as well as the beſt of <hi>friends,</hi> and ſo to blunt the Sword of <hi>wrathful Miniſters,</hi> not by <hi>ſhunning</hi> or <hi>reſiſting,</hi> but in
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:33971:12"/>
patient meekneſs quietly <hi>yeelding</hi> thereunto, that either in <hi>life</hi> or <hi>death</hi> as <hi>the Lord ſhall chooſe,</hi> he may <hi>by faith get victory over</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf and the <hi>world.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>Remaining ſtill a Servant of <hi>Chriſt Jeſus,</hi> and a hearty well-willer to <hi>his whole Family, new-named of him</hi> in the <hi>earthly</hi> as well as in the <hi>heavenly Nature.</hi>
            </q>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:33971:12"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
